<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on HomotopyContinuation.jl</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on HomotopyContinuation.jl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:56:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The point of maximal curvature on a surface</title>
      <link>/blog/curvature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/curvature/</guid>
      <description>(Update Sept. 4 2018: there have been some typos in the first version of this post. They have been fixed.)
In a recent discussion with Maddie Weinstein and Khazhgali Kozhasov we considered the problem of computing the maximal curvature of an algebraic manifold $V\subset \mathbb{R}^n$ (a smooth manifold that is also a real algebraic variety ).
Our definition of maximal curvature is $\sigma: = \mathrm{sup}_{p\in V} \sigma(p)$, where $\sigma(p)$ is the maximal curvature of a geodesic through $p$:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>/blog/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 21:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to our new homepage! Hi there!
We are excited to launch the new homepage for HomotopyContinuation.jl. We plan to keep you here updated with the latest development news, interesting applications and general thoughts. If you use HomotopyContinuation.jl and want to share your experience get in touch with us!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaulay2 interface for HomotopyContinuation.jl</title>
      <link>/blog/macaulay2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 18:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/macaulay2/</guid>
      <description>Tim Duff pushed a very first version of a Macaulay2 interface to his Github repo. It is available in the &amp;ldquo;Julia&amp;rdquo; branch. The current version lets you export polynomials into .jl files or call HomotopyContinuation.jl directly from Macaulay2.
For instance, the following M2 code generates the file mypolynomial.jl (I assume that the functions from the Julia branch have been loaded into the current session).
R = QQ[x, y] f = {x^2 + y^2, x-y} writeSys(PolySystem f, &amp;quot;mypolynomial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The number of circles that are tangent to 3 given conics</title>
      <link>/blog/circles_conics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 21:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/circles_conics/</guid>
      <description>In the previous blog entry I mentioned the Macaulay2 interface for HomotopyContinuation.jl that is currently under development. In this blog post I want to show how useful this interface can be.
Consider the problem of computing all circles that are tangent to 3 given conics $C_1,C_2,C_3 \subset \mathbb{R}^2$. For instance, the following picture shows 14 circles that are tangent to $$C_1 = \{y=-x^2+2x+5\}, C_2 = \{y = 2x^2+5x-8\}, C_3 = \{y = 8x^2-3x-2\}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sascha @ International Congress on Mathematical Software</title>
      <link>/blog/icms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 19:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/icms/</guid>
      <description>Sascha will present the features of HomotopyContinuation.jl at the International Congress on Mathematical Software at Notre Dame this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer School on Numerical Computing in Algebraic Geometry at MPI Leipzig</title>
      <link>/blog/nag_summer_school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 20:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nag_summer_school/</guid>
      <description>To use the true power of homotopy continuation algorithms the user should be familiar with both algebraic geometry and numerical mathematics. If you want to learn more about the relations of those two, you should come to the Summer School on Numerical Computing in Algebraic Geometry at MPI Leipzig.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>