<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on HomotopyContinuation.jl</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on HomotopyContinuation.jl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 21:56:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensor decomposition and homotopy continuation</title>
      <link>/blog/cpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 21:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/cpd/</guid>
      <description>In this blog I want to repeat the computations from the article &amp;ldquo;Homotopy Techniques for Tensor Decomposition and Perfect Identifiability&amp;rdquo; by Hauenstein, Oeding, Ottaviani and Sommese. In that article they compute the number of canonical polyadic decompositions (CPD) of a random $2\times 2\times 2\times 3$-tensor by using the monodromy method. It is known that with probability one a random complex $2\times 2\times 2\times 3$-tensor has rank equal to 4:
$$ T = \sum_{i=1}^4 a_i \otimes b_i \otimes c_i \otimes d_i,$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tritangents</title>
      <link>/blog/tritangents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 21:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tritangents/</guid>
      <description>A complex sextic curve in $\mathbb{C}^3$ is the intersection of a cubic surface $\mathcal{C}\subset \mathbb{C}^3$ with a quadric $\mathcal{Q}\subset \mathbb{C}^3$; that is, there exist polynomials in three variables $C$ of degree 3 and $Q$ of degree 2, such that $\mathcal{C} = \{x\in\mathbb{C}^3 : C(x) = 0\}$ and $\mathcal{Q} = \{x\in\mathbb{C}^3 : Q(x) = 0\}$.
An interesting fact about such sextic curves is that they have 120 complex tritangents (at least almost all of them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The point of maximal curvature on a surface</title>
      <link>/blog/curvature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 11:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/curvature/</guid>
      <description>In a recent discussion with Maddie Weinstein and Khazhgali Kozhasov we considered the problem of computing the maximal curvature of an algebraic manifold $V\subset \mathbb{R}^n$ (a smooth manifold that is also a real algebraic variety ).
Our definition of maximal curvature is $\sigma: = \mathrm{sup}_{p\in V} \sigma(p)$, where $\sigma(p)$ is the maximal curvature of a geodesic through $p$:
$$\sigma(p): = \mathrm{max} \,\{\Vert \ddot{\gamma}(0)\Vert \mid \gamma \in V \text{ geodesic w.\ } \gamma(0)=p, \Vert \dot{\gamma}(0)\Vert = 1\}$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>/blog/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 21:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to our new homepage! Hi there!
We are excited to launch the new homepage for HomotopyContinuation.jl. We plan to keep you here updated with the latest development news, interesting applications and general thoughts. If you use HomotopyContinuation.jl and want to share your experience get in touch with us!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaulay2 interface for HomotopyContinuation.jl</title>
      <link>/blog/macaulay2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 18:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/macaulay2/</guid>
      <description>Tim Duff pushed a very first version of a Macaulay2 interface to his Github repo. It is available in the &amp;ldquo;Julia&amp;rdquo; branch. The current version lets you export polynomials into .jl files or call HomotopyContinuation.jl directly from Macaulay2.
For instance, the following M2 code generates the file mypolynomial.jl (I assume that the functions from the Julia branch have been loaded into the current session).
R = QQ[x, y] f = {x^2 + y^2, x-y} writeSys(PolySystem f, &amp;quot;mypolynomial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3264 conics tangent to five conics</title>
      <link>/blog/3264/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 21:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/3264/</guid>
      <description>A conic in the plane $\mathbb{R}^2$ is the zero set of a quadratic polynomial in two variables:
$$ \,\, a_1 x^2 \,+\, a_2 xy \,+\, a_3 y^2 \, +\, a_4 x \, + \, a_5 y \, + \, a_6 \,.$$
Geometrically, a conic can be either a circle, an ellipse, a hyperbola, a parabola or a union of two lines. The last case is a degenerate conic. Double lines are allowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The number of circles that are tangent to 3 given conics</title>
      <link>/blog/circles_conics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 21:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/circles_conics/</guid>
      <description>Consider the problem of computing all circles that are tangent to 3 conics $C_1,C_2,C_3 \subset \mathbb{R}^2$. For instance, the following picture shows 14 circles that are tangent to $$C_1 = \{y=-x^2+2x+5\}, C_2 = \{y = 2x^2+5x-8\}, C_3 = \{y = 8x^2-3x-2\}.$$
Emiris and Tzoumas write that there are 184 complex circles that are tangent to 3 general conics. This means, that there are 184 complex solutions $(a_1,a_2,r)$ such that there exists some $(x,y)\in\mathbb{C}^2$ with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do It Yourself</title>
      <link>/blog/do-it-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 20:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/do-it-yourself/</guid>
      <description>A conic in the plane $\mathbb{R}^2$ is the zero set of a quadratic polynomial in two variables:
$$\,\, a_1 x^2 \,+\, a_2 xy \,+\, a_3 y^2 \, +\, a_4 x \, + \, a_5 y \, + \, a_6 \,.$$ Geometrically, a conic can be either a circle, an ellipse, a hyperbola, a parabola or a union of two lines. The last case is called a degenerate conic.
Steiner&amp;rsquo;s conic problem asks the question of how many conics are tangent to five given conics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sascha @ International Congress on Mathematical Software</title>
      <link>/blog/icms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 19:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/icms/</guid>
      <description>Sascha will present the features of HomotopyContinuation.jl at the International Congress on Mathematical Software at Notre Dame this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer School on Numerical Computing in Algebraic Geometry at MPI Leipzig</title>
      <link>/blog/nag_summer_school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 20:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/nag_summer_school/</guid>
      <description>To use the true power of homotopy continuation algorithms the user should be familiar with both algebraic geometry and numerical mathematics. If you want to learn more about the relations of those two, you should come to the Summer School on Numerical Computing in Algebraic Geometry at MPI Leipzig.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>